Hello everyone, welcome you once again to
our new video today.  So
today in this video I am going to discuss with you
about Aditya Birla Sun Life Multi Assistance Elocation Fund Diet Growth.  In this video, I
will discuss with you what returns this mutual fund has
given in the last 1 year, 3 years or annual returns?
What is the price of one NAB as of today?  This is how many
star rating mutual funds have.
What is the minimum SIP amount you can invest in this?
And what is their fund size?  Along with this, I
will discuss with you which
stocks are listed in these and if you had
deposited some money in these mutual funds, then
what returns would you have seen in the last 1 year or 3 years.  Let's
talk about Aditya
Birla Sun Life Multi Assist Elocation Fund
Diet Growth. This is a hybrid category
mutual fund which
comes under the Multi Assist Elocation category and it is a
very high risk mutual fund.  If we
talk about their returns of last 1 year, then the
returns given in last 1 year is
22.43%.  Talking about 3 years, there
is a return of 20.22% in 3 years.
And if we talk about annual returns, the annual
return is 20.26%.
This was their long term return.   At the
same time, if we talk about their short term returns, then the
returns given in the last 1 month are 0.55% and if we
talk about 6 months, then the returns given in 6 months are 14.47%.
Now let's talk about their NAV.   As of
today, its NAV price is
₹17.46. The
minimum SIP amount you can invest in it is ₹100.
That is, if you want to start your investment as SIP in Aditya Birla Sun Life
Multi Assist One Location Fund, then
you can start from ₹100.
Their fund size is Rs
5588 crore.  That is, till now the
total investment in Aditya Birla Sun Life Multi Assist One Location Fund is
₹5588 crores and if we
talk about its expense ratio, then
its expense ratio is 0.56%. Now let us talk about
what new investors and old investors will do here, so those who
are new investors, you can start your investment in either SIP or Lumpsum.
Talking about the target, what is the target going to be?   Is.  The
target period for SIP will be
minimum 6 years and the target period for lump sum will
be minimum 3 years.  If
you invest in these mutual funds for this long,
you will get very good returns.   If we
talk about those who have already
invested in these, then you will
continue your investment because
these mutual funds are
giving higher returns than other mutual funds category.
Now let us talk about the return calculator and see
what returns you would get if you deposited some money in these mutual funds.
Basically there are
two types of investment.  One
is SIP and the
other is lumpsum.  I will
talk about both the categories, what returns would you get if you had deposited some money in SIP
and what returns would you have got if you had deposited some money in lump sum.
First let's talk
about SIP and I am assuming
that if you were to
deposit ₹5,000 per month in this mutual fund,
what returns would you get.  If
you had deposited ₹5,000 per month in this mutual fund, then the
money deposited in 3 months would have been
₹15,000 and you would have got
₹15.33 i.e. a
return of 2.22%.  Talking about 1 year,
your total money deposited in 1 year is
₹0000 and you get ₹67318 with a
return of 12.20%.  Talking about 3 years,
your total money deposited in 3 years is
₹180 and
you get ₹238312.
Returns of 32.40% could have been seen here.
This was about SIP.  Now let's talk about
lumpsum and I am assuming
that what would have happened if you had deposited ₹1 lakh in this mutual fund at one go
?
In 3 months your ₹1 lakh would have become ₹11858.
Returns of 1.86%.  Your
₹1 lakh becomes ₹122430 in 1 year.
Returns of 22.43% and
your ₹1 lakh becomes ₹173752 in 3 years.
Returns of 73.75% can be
seen here.  Now let's talk about
holdings, the total number of
stocks listed in these is 101 stocks.
If we discuss the top 10 and their
sector wise, then the first name that comes is Aadat
Birla Sunlife Gold ETF which
comes in an ETF category.  Aditya Birla
Sunlife Silver ETF Growth which
falls under the silver category.  Reliance
Industrial LED Energy B Airtel LED
Communication HDFC Banked Finance Axis
Bank LED Finance
ICICI Banked Finance Kotak Mahindra Bank
LED Finance Infosys LED Technology &
Swiggi is in the field of LED Services.
If we talk about their holding analysis, then
61.92% is on equity, 16.20% is on commodities,
10.26% is on debt, 5.747% is on cash,
4.65% is on real estate and 1.49% is on hedge equity.
Their equity sector talks about one location.  That
means, if you invest
your money in these mutual funds, then in
which
sectors and at what percentage will your money be divided and invested
?  So Financial Pay is 33.34,
Technology Pay is 15.28, Consumer Distary is
9.88, Energy & Utilities is 9.46, Consumer
Step is 9.19, Industrial is 7.71, Material is 7.06,
Health Care is 6.28, Real Estate is 1.12 and
Unspecified Pay is 0.69%.  At the same time, if we
talk about their debt sector location, then
Financial is at 48.87, Construction is at
26.19, Sober Gran is at 11.93, Capital Goods is at
4.98, Energy is at 3.02, Communication is at 2.99
and Others is at 2.02%.
If we talk about their advance ratio, then their Price to
Earning Ratio is at 24.49 and PB Ratio is at
3.75.
If you want to invest in these mutual funds,
then
what will be the minimum amount you will need?  If you
want to invest in Aditya Birla Sunlight Multi Asset Single Location Fund in lump sum, then the minimum investment will be
₹500 and if you
want to start your investment through SIP
then you can start with ₹100.
Now let's talk about returns and ranking
and first of all let's talk about the fund return of Aditya
Birla Sun Life Multi Assist Ek Location
Fund which is 14.5 in 6 months,
22.4 in 1 year, 30.2 in 3 years and
annual is 20.3, whereas the
average returns of this category i.e. Hybrid
Multi Assist Ekation Fund is 8.6 in 6 months,
15.1 in 1 year and 17.8 in 3 years.
So from here we will see that these mutual funds have
always given returns higher than their category average for 6 months, 1 year or 3 years.
Now let's talk about their
exit load.  If you
withdraw more than 30% of your investment within 1 year,
then you will have to pay an exit load of 1%.
Talking about stamp duty, the
stamp duty is 0.5%.   Let's
talk about tax implication.  If you
withdraw the invested money within 2 years, then you will have to pay tax as per the returns whichever income
tax slab you fall under.
And if you
withdraw your money from it after 2 years, then
you will have to pay tax of 12.5% ​​on the returns.
If we talk about similar funds around this, then there are
many such
similar funds around this, you can see from here,
one of which has given better returns than Aditya Birla Sun Life
Multi Assist Elocation Fund,
being in the same category,
whose name is Nipon India Multi
Assist Elocation Fund Daily Growth, whose
one year return is 23.35, 3 year return is 22.67
and fund size is 10661 crores, let us
see a short overview about what we have seen till now.
Aditya Birla Sun Life Multi Assist Ek
Location Fund Diet Growth This is a hybrid
category mutual fund which has been launched by
Aditya Birla Sun Life Mutual Fund.
Dhawalgala is the current fund manager of this fund. The
current asset under management of this fund
is ₹43736
crore and the latest NAV is ₹17.46
Aditya Birla Sun Life Multi Assist Ek Location
Fund Diet Growth This is a very high risk
mutual fund. In this the minimum SIP amount has been
set at ₹100 and the minimum lumpsum has
also been set at ₹500.  If you
withdraw more than 30% of your investment within 1 year, then you will have to pay an exit load of 1%.
And if we talk about their fund benchmark, the
data of their fund benchmark is not available right now.  So today in this video
I discussed with you about Aditya
Birla Sun Life Multi Assist One Location
Fund.  So we will meet
next time with some good information about this type of video.